Lui Sheng Jie

Email: luishengjie@outlook.com

Skype: live:luishengjie

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/luishengjie

Website: http://luishengjie.github.io

Summary

Final year Computer Engineering Undergraduate from the National University of Singapore (NUS). I will be graduating in December 2019 and have prior experiences in Computer Vision and Software Development.

I was part of the team at Good For Food where I researched and experimented on various machine learning models for food waste classification. I was responsible for the development of their initial food waste image recognition prototype and was also involved in providing technical demonstrations to stakeholders.

Currently, I am interning at Vebits AI, a start-up that utilises Computer Vision to address issues due to traffic fatalities. I am involved in developing an end-to-end solution for driver behaviour recognition which involves data preparation, testing and fine-tuning deep learning models for real-time behaviour recognition. I am also involved in developing software applications (Android / PyQt) used for deployment.

Education

Aug 2016 – Present	National University of Singapore Bachelor of Computing (Honours) in Computer Engineering (4.37 / 5.0)	Singapore
Aug 2014 – Aug 2016	National Service	Singapore
Aug 2011 – Jan 2014	Nanyang Polytechnic Diploma in Electrical Engineering with Eco-Design (Merit)	Singapore
Work Experience		
May 2019 – Present	Vebits Computer Vision Engineer Intern Develop data collection pipeline to collect training data used to train deep learning models. Train and deploy deep learning model for driver behaviour recognition.	Singapore
May 2018 – Nov 2018	 Good For Food Software Engineer Intern (Computer Vision / Machine Learning) Research and experiment on machine learning models for food waste image recognition. Responsible for the development of Good For Food's food waste image recognition system (prototype) Provide technical demonstrations to key stakeholders 	Singapore
Feb 2018 – April 2018	SGDriven Android Developer (Intern) Worked on camera related issues due to Android fragmentation Testing and Debugging	Singapore
Jan 2018 - Feb 2018	Stylo Industries Android Developer (Intern) - Worked on the minimum viable product for the Stylo Android app	Singapore
May 2017 – July 2017	NUS Office of Student Affairs Web Developer - Developed the microsite used for NUS Freshman Orientation Camp 2017	Singapore

Scholastic Achievements/Extracurricular Activities

May 2019 – Present	NUS Orbital Summer Programme - Advisor for the Orbital Summer Programme	Singapore
Sep 2018 – Jan 2018	Udacity Deep Learning Nanodegree - Completed the Udacity Deep Learning Nanodegree	MMOC
May 2018 – Nov 2018	 NUS Overseas College (Singapore) Completed the NUS Overseas College Singapore programmed (NCSG 22) Interned at Good For Food as a Software Engineer working on Food Waste Image Recognition 	Singapore
May 2018 – August 2018	 NUS Orbital Summer Programme Advisor for the Orbital Summer Programme Prepared and curated the content for the Android Development workshop 	Singapore
May 2017 – August 2017	NUS Orbital Summer Programme - Completed the NUS Orbital Summer programme (Project Gemini)	Singapore
May 2015	Singapore Power Bronze Medal	Singapore
Nov 2013 - April 2014	Singapore Amazing Flying Machine Competition (SAFMC) - Champion award (Gold) - Best Performance award (Silver)	Singapore
April 2013 - April 2014	Directors List (Nanyang Polytechnic) Semester 1, Semester 2	Singapore
April 2012 - April 2013	Directors List (Nanyang Polytechnic) Semester 1, Semester 2	Singapore
Aug 2011 - April 2012	Directors List (Nanyang Polytechnic) Semester 2	Singapore

Skill Sets & Proficiency

Programming	Java Python C	Proficient Proficient Intermediate
Framework & Libraries	OpenCV TensorFlow + Keras PyTorch Android Studio Flask PyQt	Proficient Intermediate Intermediate Intermediate Intermediate Intermediate
Server Management	Google Compute Engine	Intermediate
Language Proficiency	1	

Spoken	English – fluent; Mandarin – fluent
Written	English – competent; Chinese – basic